# **Jeffrey Bialba**

Tel: **+1 717 685 9968** 

I have over 7 years of hands-on experience in handling AWS infrastructure for high availability, fault-tolerance, disaster recovery, orchestration, Infrastructure as Code, security compliance, and CI/CD integration.

I am a constant learner, self-motivated, and a dedicated full-time freelancer with attention to detail and adhere to best practices.

My TOOLKIT;

Amazon Web Services:

- · EC2
- · ECS
- · EKS
- ·VPC
- · S3
- CloudFront
- ·ALB
- · RDS
- · Elastic Beanstalk
- · Lambda

DevOps:

Docker

Kubernetes

· Terraform

Jenkins

· CodePipeline

· CodeBuild

Bitbucket

 $\cdot$  Github

Scripting and Automation
· Bash
• Python
1) SQL Server 2008, 2012 database design
2) C# MVC with integrations with any database including MySQL and SQL Server
3) ASP.NET
4) C# web forms
5) PHP
6) jQuery and Ajax

- Database table design for MS SQL and MySQL

Database Design Experience

Your website tables require efficient indexing and key placement. Without these elements, your website loses performance. I've designed key database tables that support large, enterprise applications. My services provide table design, data import and stored procedure programming

- Stored Procedures and SQL Programming

Stored procedures are database objects that process data retrieval. I provide stored procedures for MySQL and any version of Microsoft SQL Server. Stored procedures should be implemented in place of inline SQL to avoid SQL injection hacks.

# Web Development

- Dynamic content is a must-have for any website. I can provide a dynamic website in any .NET language -- C# or VB.NET. These two languages provide core services and interaction with any database including MS SQL or MySQL.
- W3 validation provides accurate code. Accurate code provides better indexing in Google, since you are ensured the bot is able to properly parse your site. My code is W3 validated for accuracy.
- Simple HTML setups. I can also set up a simple website with HTML content and paging.

## My skill set is as follows:

Ruby, Ruby on Rails 3/4/5

- -Python 9 rating
- Java 9 rating
- PHP 7.x 9 rating
- C# ASP.NET MVC 9 rating
- Laravel Framework (5.x) 9 rating
- Mysql/Postgres 9
- React / Redux 9
- AngularJS (1.x, 4+) 10

- RXJS 10
- socket.io + Pusher + PubNub 9
- Linux/Apache/Nginx/Varnish Cache 9
- Stripe Billing/Subscriptions 9
- Pusher 9
- Composer 9
- BDD/TDD Unit Testing / Protractor / Selenium 8
- Jenkins / Bamboo CI 8
- GIT 9
- Wordpress 9
- Docker/Vagrant 9
- Redis 9
- AWS / s3 / Route 53 / ECS / EC2 9
- GruntJS/Gulp 9
- Node/NPM/Yarn 9
- AWS Serverless 9

# **API Development:**

Twilio

Tesseract

PyTesseract

Backtrader

OpenCV

Pyfolio

OpenGL

Stripe
BrainTree
Qualifications:
- Various RDBMSs (MySQL, PostgreSQL, H2)
- noSQL DBs (MongoDB, Cassandra)
- OSGi (Apache Felix)
- Kafka
- Akka
- Networking (Netty, Apache MINA)
- Reactive extensions (rxjava, rxjavafx)
- Java bytecoding (ASM)
- git
- JUnit
- Maven
- Jenkins
- AWS
Experiences:
Total of 4 years experiences

Tensorflow

Java - 4 years

PHP – 4 years

NodeJS – 3 years

Javascript – 4 years

Angular JS – 2 years

Python – 4 years

REACT – 3 years

AWS Lambda – 3 years

Firebase – 4 years

Total of 4 years mobile app development experience

- Xamarin – 4 years

Native mobile app development with

- Objective-C (for iOS) 4 years
- Java (for Android) 4 years

### **Work History:**

#### FullStack Devs

December 2017 - October 2018

Sr. Developer & Project Manager

- deployed and maintained kiosks software of cryptocurrency ATMs all over the world
- Setting up Blockchain explorer for several clients, including Fenix Coin and Moore chain. This requires Node. Js server and Node. Js app to establish connection with wallet / full node and gather all information in Mongo so client can query through webUI - results are here:

### PandaSoft - Philippines Company

Jan 2016 – Feb 2017

- · Planned, designed, and built a variety of features for web based applications
- · Worked collaboratively using git/github repository management and workflow
- Built uploaders and exporters, business reports, and PDF/CSV generators
- · Created modular and maintainable Service Objects for API integration

ImagineWeb Solutions – Philippines company

August 2015 – Jan 2016

- Working mainly with Node. Js and all sort of frameworks, creating dashboards with javascript and with help of server side events, mongodb, redis etc.. also doing ruby programming and a lot of infographic designs.
- Worked on several web sites and systems using jQuery, CSS, AJAX, Flash / Flash Media Server / Wowza Media Server

## **Projects:**

Web Development

https://www.4seasonsstore.co.uk/

I have integrated the company and the employment management module on this project.

http://virtualrealestateshop.com

### **Drupal work**

http://www.mtm.sangar.ee/

http://strack.webassist.me/

http://www.bugtenders.club/

http://prank-bjmoov.up.st/

#### Joomla work

http://samanthacharbonneau.com/

A client with a dated Joomla 1.5 website wanted the website upgraded to Joomla 3.7. Not only did i upgraded the website to Joomla 3.7, i rebuilt it from scratch using Joomla 3.7, built a modern mobile responsive template and implemented several tweaks to make it secure and give it a modern and professional look and feel.

http://www.homeonthefrio.com

The client needed a website to advertise and sell a house. I built the website using Joomla 3.7. The website was built to be mobile responsive, optimized for speed and showcased all the relevant details about the house.

Refreshed Joomla website with a new design to increase accessibility across mobile devices and improve user engagement.

http://www.windsorlife.com/